vkudari@buffalo.edu https://vinaykudari.me +1-469-943-6778

**Profile:** Masters student who has been developing software systems for over 5 years and professionally for 3.5 years. Vinay has experience leading projects with vague requirements and known for writing clean maintainable code.

#### Relevant skills

Python, Go, JAVA, SQL, Django, Flask, PyTorch, PySpark, Docker, Kubernetes, Git, Redis, Kafka, GCP, AWS

### EXPERIENCE

#### Playstation (Sony)

San Francisco, CA

Software Development Intern | java, kafka, concurrency, async, no-sql, cassandra

May 2022 - Present

- Worked on auto follow feature for PS5 Explore Hub. Message queues and REST endpoints were developed
- o Learned custom framework and leveraged asynchronous programming pattern to optimise the latency for 1M QPS traffic
- o Developed a cross platform CLI tool to automate generation of grafana analytical dashboards from logs

#### **Brave Orbit**

(Remote) Capetown, South Africa

Full Stack Developer | python, rest-api, django, mobile-app, pytest, redis, gcp, k8s

Jan 2020 - Aug 2021

- Programmed a cross-platform app using BLoC pattern, implemented database, network and state management layers
- Engineered HIPAA compliant scalable async push notification service for medication reminder application
- o Developed a task scheduler for clinical surveys that delivers email, SMS alerts and gathers response on a recurring basis
- Architected a custom ERP system with multi-product substitutions and combo-product life cycle tracking features
- Setup Kubernetes CI/CD workflows to automatically test, build and deploy backend services on cloud
- o Streamlined automated testing pipelines and improved test coverage for both frontend and backend services

#### Accenture

Bangalore, India

Big Data Developer | redshift, pyspark, pandas, aws, distributed-systems

Sep 2018 - Dec 2019

- o Performed time series analysis on drug assay data to identify raw materials that effect the drug quality
- o Designed ETL data validation pipeline using micro service architecture; Manual testing resources were cut by 70%
- $\circ$  Developed PL/SQL procedures to generate parent child hierarchies using temporal drug life cycle data

# Visakhapatnam Port Trust

Visakhapatnam, India

Computer Vision Intern | opency, scikit-learn, numpy, video processing

May 2017 - July 2017

o Extracted frames from surveillance cameras; merged them based on SIFT keypoints and RANSAC; trained a SVM to detect cargo type and estimate lease area; developed a motion detector model to identify suspicious movements

#### Projects

- Full text search engine (search, information-retrieval): Developed a query parser to transform search query into boolean expression; Optimised the text retrieval by creating inverted index and performed batch processing.
- Recommender system using graph neural networks (gnn, deep-learning): Developed an inductive matrix completion model using user-item node embeddings pretrained on movie reviews; 1-hop sub graphs are used to forecast ratings
- Computer vision based vehicle damage detector api (vision, rest-api, django, pytorch): Trained an instance segmentation model to detect damages; assigned a health score based on relative area of damage and deployed as an api
- Unordered image stitching and deghosting (vision, image matching): Estimated approximate overlap area by minimum variance technique on binarized images; stitched images based on binary tree model; removed deghosting from the overlap areas by selecting regions based on minimum local gradients
- Open-source contributions (nlp, open-source): Core contributor to HuggingFace Datasets official repository
- Information extraction as seq2seq task (nlp, transformer, text2text): Transformed labelled structured data into text; finetuned T5 model to generate text and extracted entities using REGEX
- Abstractive text summarization of tabular data (nlp, transformer): Flattened tables into sequence of words, preserved structure using key:value format; Explored various text2text models to generate summary of news articles
- Deep learning based serverless rest api (serverless, rest-api, cloud-run, ci/cd): Created synthetic face mask dataset and developed automated pipeline to build, test and deploy trained model in a docker container to google cloud run
- Reinforcement learning based crypto trading bot (time-series): Designed a continuous action space OpenAI gym environment to handle trading data; LSTM with CNN was used as function approximator to actor critic algorithms

## EDUCATION

# University at Buffalo [3.95/4.0 GPA]

Buffalo, NY

Master of Science in Computer Science (AI/ML Specialization)

Sep 2021 - Present

Courses: Data Structure & Algorithms, Distributed Systems, Computer Vision, NLP, Deep Learning, Big Data Systems, RL Research: Finding inconsistency between text and related images, advised by Prof. David Doermann

## National Institute of Technology, Durgapur [3.3/4.0 GPA]

West Bengal, India

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering

July 2014 - May 2018

Courses: Operating Systems, Computer Architecture, Networking, Database Management Systems, Compilers, Digital Image Processing Thesis: Gender Classification using CNN advised by Dr. Dakshina Ranjan Kisku

# Publications

• Time series analysis of civil unrest using Graph Neural Networks @ COLING 2022 (In Review):